<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linn Sofie Sæther</title>
    <link>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Linn Sofie Sæther</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://linnsofies.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Canonical Correlation Analysis (CCA) in R</title>
      <link>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/blog/cca_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/blog/cca_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>What is CCA? Link to heading When our statistician recommended we use a CCA on our data, I have to admit I had never heard of it before. I was surprised to find out that it is a very powerful alternative to running several multivariate regressions or dimension reduction techniques like Principal Component Analysis (PCA) or Independent Component Analysis (ICA), which can sometimes be challenging to interpret.
Canonical Correlation Analysis (CCA) is similar to PCA, but with some important differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive plots with Plotly (coming!)</title>
      <link>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/blog/interactive_plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 19:42:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/blog/interactive_plotly/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial is on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi!</title>
      <link>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Linn Sofie, I am a neuroscientist and PhD candidate affiliated with the Oslo University Hospital/University of Oslo and the Norwegian Centre for Mental Disorders Research (NORMENT).
In my PhD project I am investigating the role of low-grade inflammation in cognitive impairment &amp;ndash; a common symptom in severe mental illnesses including schizophrenia and bipolar spectrum disorders. The project involves analysis of inflammatory and immune-related markers both at the periphery (blood) and centrally (brain).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/publications/</guid>
      <description>Here you will find a list of my published works, including popular science blog posts, media interviews and first/co-authored publications. For the most recent updates, you can check out my Google Scholar profile.
Popular science blogs &amp;amp; media interviews Link to heading LS Sæther, T Ueland, OA Andreassen, A Szabo, T Ueland (2023). Does inflammation get on our nerves? Nature Portfolio: Behind the Paper.
Interview in Norwegian (2023). Schizofreni forbindes med betennelser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://linnsofies.netlify.app/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you have any questions, you can reach me at: l.s.saether@psykologi.uio.no</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
